Once discovered, it was changed forever.
The New World is a drama, history, romance film directed by Terrence Malick.
A drama about explorer John Smith and the clash between Native
Americans and English settlers in the 17th century.
Captain Smith, played by Colin Farrell.
Pocahontas, played by Q'orianka Kilcher.
Captain Newport, played by Christopher Plummer.
John Rolfe, played by Christian Bale.
Powhatan, played by August Schellenberg.
Opechancanough, played by Wes Studi.
The New World is a 2005 historical romantic drama film written and directed by Terrence Malick, depicting the founding of the Jamestown, Virginia,
settlement and inspired by the historical figures Captain John Smith, Pocahontas of the Powhatan tribe, and Englishman John Rolfe.
It is the fourth feature film written and directed by Malick.
The cast includes Colin Farrell, Q'orianka Kilcher, Christopher Plummer, Christian Bale, August
Schellenberg, Wes Studi, David Thewlis, Yorick van Wageningen and John Savage.
The production team includes director of photography Emmanuel Lubezki, producer Sarah Green, production designer Jack Fisk, costume
designer Jacqueline West, composer James Horner and film editors Richard Chew, Hank Corwin, Saar Klein and Mark Yoshikawa.
The New World was a box-office failure even though it received many award nominations
for Lubezki's cinematography, Kilcher's acting and Horner's score.
The film was initially met with an only mildly positive critical response, although
several critics later ranked it as one of the best films of the decade.
The film explores themes of native american, native american
attack, interracial romance, colonialism, virginia.
The tone is emotional.